trekitt.co.uk 2017-08-10

# Trekitt | Privacy Policy & Cookies

###  Data Protection and Privacy policy

We respect the privacy of all individuals who use this Website. This privacy policy explains what information we gather from you, how we use it and how you may control our use of your personal information. We will ensure that all personal information supplied is held securely, in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. This Website contains links to other websites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other websites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our Website and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Website.

Trekitt is the sole owner of the information collected on this Website. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. Your privacy is of the highest importance to us, and we promise never to release your personal details to any outside company for mailing or marketing purposes without your express permission.

What information we collect:

  * Information that you provide to us when setting up or amending an account with us.  For example, your name, address, various delivery addresses, email address, contact telephone numbers password, password question and answer, and card details which can be used when you subsequently place an order.
  * Information that you provide to us when placing an order online or by filling in any online registration form which we may make available on our Website. For example, your name, email address, payment address and card details which are essential for processing an order.
  * Information which you voluntarily disclose to us by email or other means.
  * Information about your computer including, where available, your IP address, operating system and browser type.
  * Information about your internet usage obtained using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer.

###  Surveys and Contests

From time-to-time our Website requests information from its users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as post code, age level). Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this Website.

What we do with the information:

  * Internal analysis purposes within Trekitt.
  * Create and maintain your account with us;
  * To comply with our obligations following your order as set out in our terms and conditions of sale.
  * To provide regular updates and newsletters in respect of our products and services.
  * To ensure that content from our Website is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer.
  * To administer and otherwise perform our obligations in relation to the goods and/or services which we have agreed to provide to you. For example, we may use an outside carrier company to deliver orders, and a credit card processing company to bill you for goods and services. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes.
  * To provide you with information and services including any marketing that you have requested from us and otherwise to respond to queries which you may submit.
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our Website where you have chosen to do so.
  * To notify you about changes to our Website.
  * To offer you products and services provided by us or any other company within the same group of companies. You should be aware that if we are requested by the police or any other regulatory or government authority investigating suspected illegal activities to provide your personal information and/or user information, we are entitled to do so.

Correcting and updating Personal Information:

 If a user's personally identifiable information changes (such as your post code), or if a user no longer desires our service, we will endeavour to provide a way to correct, update or remove that user's personal data provided to us. This can easily be done by emailing [support@trekitt.co.uk](mailto:support@trekitt.co.uk)

###  Third parties who may use the information

 We may pass your data to third parties for the purposes of processing credit or debit card payments and processing your orders.

###  Your consent

During the online ordering and/or registration process you will automatically give consent for Trekitt to contact you offering promotional goods and services. Users who no longer wish to receive regular information from Trekitt may opt-out of receiving these communications by using the corresponding links or emailing us at [support@trekitt.co.uk](mailto:support@trekitt.co.uk), indicating your wish to withdraw your consent for Trekitt to the use of your personal information.

###  Security

We realise how important it is to securely store any information that you provide us. Our site (trekitt.co.uk) currently uses high-level Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption technology, the most advanced security software currently available for online transactions. You can therefore rest assured that we take the security of your payment and personal details very seriously. We may vary this in the future if we feel you will benefit from greater security whilst using our website.

You can tell whether a webpage is secure as 'https' will replace the 'http' at the front of the www.trekitt.co.uk in your browser address window, also a small locked padlock will appear in the bottom bar of your browser window.

While we currently use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also protect your information off-line. All of your information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted to our office. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job are granted access to your personal information. The servers on which we store your personal information are kept in a secure environment.

Verified by Visa and MasterCard SecureCode

To give you even more confidence in shopping online with trekitt.co.uk we have introduced Verified by Visa and MasterCard SecureCode. These services enhance your existing credit/debit card accounts against unauthorized use when you shop with us.

To use this service, you must first register with the bank or other organisation that issued your card.

Once you have registered and created your own private password with your card issuer, you will be automatically prompted at the checkout when the card is being processed to provide this password each time you make a purchase.

###  Phishing

Phishing is the practice of tricking someone into giving confidential information. Examples include falsely claiming to be a legitimate company when sending an email to a user, in an attempt to get the user to send private information that will be used for identity theft and fraud.  Trekitt will never ask you to send any personal details via email. If we require such details, for security reasons we will ask you to contact us by telephone. Should you receive an email claiming to be from Trekitt or Trek Kit (Hereford) Ltd requesting this kind of information please do not respond but contact us immediately.

###  Complaints

If you feel that Trekitt is not abiding by its posted privacy policy, you should first email Paul Trepte at paul@trekitt.co.uk. You can also write to Paul at:

Paul Trepte  
Trekitt  
51 Eign Gate  
Hereford  
HR4 0AB

### Our Website Cookies Policy

A cookie is a small file of text which we transfer to your hard drive through your web browser, as with most websites, when you visit our website and use certain pages or features on the site, especially when placing an order. It enables our own system to recognise you when you visit our website again and improve our service to you. This information can be used to enhance the content of our website and make your use of it easier. For more information about cookies please visit www.allaboutcookies.org

### Cookies

When we provide services, we want to make them easy, useful and reliable. Where services are delivered on the internet, this sometimes involves placing small amounts of information on your device, for example, computer or mobile phone. These include small files known as cookies. They cannot be used to identify you personally. 

These pieces of information are used to improve services for you through, for example: 

\- enabling a service to recognise your device so you don't have to give the same information several times during one task  
\- recognising that you may already have given a username and password so you don't need to do it for every web page requested  
\- measuring how many people are using services, so they can be made easier to use and there's enough capacity to ensure they are fast 

You can manage these small files yourself and learn more about them through Internet browser cookies - what they are and how to manage them. 

### Our use of cookies

When we provide services, we want to make them easy, useful and reliable. Where services are delivered on the internet, this sometimes involves placing small amounts of information on your device, for example, your computer or mobile phone. These include small files known as cookies. They cannot be used to identify you personally. 

These pieces of information are used to improve services for you through, for example: 

\- recognising that you may already have given a username and password so you don't need to do it for every web page requested  
\- measuring how many people are using services, so they can be made easier to use and there's enough capacity to ensure they are fast  
\- analysing anonymised data to help us understand how people interact with govt services so we can make them better 

You can manage these small files and learn more about them from the article, Internet Browser cookies- what they are and how to manage them. 

Learn how to [remove cookies set on your device.](http://www.aboutcookies.org/Default.aspx?page=1%27Our%20use%20of%20cookies%27)

There are two types of cookie you may encounter when using Trekitt : 

**First party cookies:** these are our own cookies, controlled by us and used to provide information about usage of our site. 

**Third party cookies:** these are cookies found in other companies' internet tools which we are using to enhance our site, for example Facebook or Twitter have their own cookies, which are controlled by them. 

### First party cookies

*Trekitt uses cookies in several places - we've listed each of them below with more details about why we use them and how long they will last. 

We will endeavour to let you know before we store a cookie on your computer. 

**Our Own PERSISTANT cookies**

**Name** | **Purpose** | **Typical content**  
---|---|---  
_Session |  This cookie speeds up your experience on our website if you visit us more than once by remembering key information if you have set your browser to allow it. For example your username when logging in, or your preferences when browsing our website.  | It is an anonymous customer ID cookie, **so we do not save any specific data about you at all** , just a unique _Session reference number  
  
**Cookies set by Trekitt website**

**Name** | **Purpose** | **Expires**  
---|---|---  
ASP.NET_SessionId  
HttpReferer  
Referer  
dd_object  |  These only last for the session (visit) to our website, and help with your movement through the website, and also let us know if you have visited from a 'Referer' i.e. another website where we may have a link, or an article about us.  | Expires on exit  
  
**Third party cookies**

We use a number of suppliers who may also set cookies on their websites' on its behalf. Trekitt do not control the dissemination of these cookies. You should check the third party websites for more information about these.

**Provider** | **Name** | **Purpose** | **More Info**  
---|---|---|---  
Google Analytics |  _utma  
_utmb  
_utmc  
_utmz  |  These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. They do not contain any personally identifiable information.  |  [Google Privacy policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en_uk/policies/privacy/)  
Add This | _atuvc |  The _atuvc cookie is created and read by our JavaScript on the client side in order to make sure the user sees the updated count if they share a page and return to it before our share count cache is updated. No data from that cookie is sent back to AddThis.  |  [Add This privacy](http://www.addthis.com/privacy/#.T8T3jdXUOUI)  
  
### Changes to this privacy policy

If this privacy policy changes in any way, we will place an updated version on this page. Regularly reviewing this page ensures that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we will share it with other parties. 

You can use the settings of your browser to block, or delete cookies as you wish. Do please note that blocking cookies may slow down your experience on our website, or cause issues with placing an order, as cookies are often required to help with a smooth checkout process! 

If you have any questions about our cookies policy or feedback please contact us on 01432 263 335 or via our contact us page link at the top of the page.
